Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Katherine and
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。我是Katherine。
here today we have almost, almost to the end of our series on giving a presentation in
今天我们差不多，差不多要结束关于做演示的系列课程了。
English. This is part 9 of 10, so this is near the end. But we've got a lot of really
英语。这是10部分中的第9部分，所以接近尾声了。但我们还有很多非常
great words and phrases for discussing what you've talked about in the last, I don't know,
很棒的一些单词和短语，用来讨论你最近聊过的事情，嗯，大概吧。
10 minutes or so. It's the summary of your speech and so that's what we're going to talk
大约10分钟左右。这是你演讲的总结，所以我们接下来要讨论这个。
about today.
关于今天。
That's right. So let's take a look at what Mr. Ford is saying in his summary and we'll
没错。那我们来看看福特先生在总结里说了什么，然后我们会——
be back in a bit.
马上回来。
Right everyone. I apologize that I can't show you the marketing campaign today, but next
各位，很抱歉今天没法给大家展示营销方案了，但下次
week you will all have the opportunity to see it for yourselves. And I have no doubt
本周你们所有人都有机会亲眼看到它。我毫不怀疑。
that you will be impressed. Let me wrap up the presentation by summarizing my key points.
你一定会印象深刻。让我总结一下我的关键点，来结束这次演示。
As I mentioned at the outset, 2010 represents a key year for Alpha Computers. The recession
正如我一开始提到的，2010年对阿尔法电脑公司来说是关键的一年。经济衰退
is hopefully behind us. It is clear to everyone in the computer industry that demand is booming,
希望这已经成为过去。计算机行业的每个人都清楚，需求正在激增。
especially in the developing markets. If we are to succeed in this ultra-competitive field
尤其是在发展中市场。如果我们想在这个竞争极其激烈的领域取得成功，
then we really need to push forward and offer our customers products that meet their needs
那么我们就得大力推进，给客户提供符合他们需求的产品。
on all levels. As I hope I've illustrated, the X420 represents the kind of computer that
在各个层面上。正如我希望我已经说明的那样，X420代表了那种电脑——
can really satisfy those needs.
真的能满足这些需求。
I gave you an idea of the kind of revenue we expect to hit in 2010 with the new X420
我跟你提过我们预计2010年新款X420能达到的收入水平。
range and believe me, this is really just the beginning. Once we establish the X420
范围很广，相信我，这真的只是开始。一旦我们确立了X420
in the market, we have plans to continue to expand our range with ever more revolutionary
在市场上，我们计划继续扩大我们的产品线，推出更多革命性的产品。
and impressive products.
以及令人印象深刻的产品。
Alpha Computers is dedicated to innovation and improvement. I really see no limit in
Alpha Computers 致力于创新和改进。我真的认为，只要我们坚持我之前强调的原则——质量、卓越和
our potential as long as we stick to the principles I stressed earlier. Quality, excellence, and
服务——我们的潜力就没有上限。
service.
服务。
Before we move on to the Q&A section, I'd really like to leave you with a quote that
在进入问答环节之前，我想用一句名言来结束今天的分享，
really sums up everything that we've discussed today and hopefully it will provide you with
这句话很好地总结了今天我们讨论的所有内容，希望它能给你们带来
the same inspiration that it gives me. As the great Henry Ford once said, quality means
和我一样的启发。正如伟大的亨利·福特曾经说过的，质量意味着
doing it right when no one is looking. Well, in fact our customers are looking. They are
在没人看着的时候也把事情做好。嗯，事实上，我们的客户正在看着。他们
looking for us to lead the way and to give them the quality that our competitors cannot.
期待我们引领方向，给他们提供竞争对手无法提供的质量。
We cannot let them down.
我们不能让他们失望。
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at some language on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了。现在让我们来看看“语言点解析”中的一些语言点。
Language Takeaway.
语言点解析。
So, Marco, at the very beginning of today's monologue, we have a phrase that basically
那么，Marco，在今天独白的开头，有一个短语基本上
means the same thing as summarize. What was that phrase?
和“总结”意思相同。那个短语是什么？
That's right. At the last sentence of the first paragraph, we see Mr. Ford say, let
没错。在第一段的最后一句，我们看到福特先生说：“让我通过总结我的关键点来结束这次演示。”所以这里的短语是
me wrap up the presentation by summarizing my key points. So the phrase there is wrap
“wrap up”。
up.
它的意思是总结、结束、终止。这是他演讲的结尾，所以“wrap
It means to conclude, to finish, to end. This is the very end of his speech and so to wrap
something up”就是结束它的意思。
something up means to finish it.
没错。所以，如果你在演讲时，有人让你“wrap
That's right. So maybe if you're giving a speech and someone is telling you to wrap
up”，
it up quickly.
快点结束吧。
That means stop.
那意思是停下。
That's right.
没错。
Please find an ending point. So wrap it up. Let's go. Come on.
请找个结束点。所以收尾吧。我们走吧。快点。
That's right. So he's wrapping it up by summarizing what he has talked about. And so he goes back
没错。所以他通过总结自己讲过的内容来收尾。然后他回到
to the very beginning and he says, as I mentioned at the outset.
最开始，他说，正如我在开头提到的。
Okay, the outset is a noun, it's a time and it means the beginning. So you might remember
好的，“outset”是一个名词，表示时间，意思是开始。你可能还记得
in parts one or two of this speech that he was talking about why 2010 is an important
在这篇演讲的第一或第二部分，他谈到为什么2010年对他们公司来说是重要的一年。
year for their company. And so this is the outset. This is the beginning. You can also
这就是“outset”，也就是开始。你也可以
say at the outset things looked bad but it turns out that they went well.
说“一开始情况看起来不好，但结果却进展顺利。”
Okay. So outset means beginning the start of something. Okay. And he also talked about
好的。所以“outset”意思是开始，某事的起点。好的。他还谈到了
how the computer industry demand is booming.
计算机行业的需求如何蓬勃发展。
All right. So booming is an interesting word because boom, the noun means boom, a sound.
好的。“booming”是个有趣的词，因为“boom”作为名词意思是爆炸声。
To explode.
爆炸。
Right. It's a sound that you hear when there's a storm. But booming means doing very well.
对。这是暴风雨时听到的声音。但“booming”意思是做得很好。
That means that in this case demand is booming. There is a lot of demand.
在这种情况下，需求正在蓬勃发展。需求很大。
That's right. So when you hear people say business is booming.
没错。所以当你听到人们说“生意兴隆”时。
That means business is going very well. It's very successful.
那意思是生意进展得很好。非常成功。
Okay. So it basically means that it's doing very well, that it's growing quickly and rapidly.
好的。所以它基本上意思是做得很好，增长迅速且快速。
So he went on to talk about the X420 and how the company has plans to keep expanding and
所以他接着谈到了X420，以及公司如何计划继续扩张。
keep coming out with ever more revolutionary and impressive products.
不断推出更具革命性和令人印象深刻的产品。
Okay. So something is a revolutionary if it changes a situation. Okay. Because revolution
好的。所以，如果某样东西改变了局面，它就是革命性的。因为革命
basically means change but not a small change, a really big change. And so a product is revolutionary
基本上意味着改变，但不是小改变，而是非常大的改变。所以，一个产品是革命性的
if it introduces something really new, really exciting.
如果它引入了真正新颖、真正令人兴奋的东西。
Okay. So an example of a revolutionary product was the home computer.
好的。那么革命性产品的一个例子就是家用电脑。
Exactly. Because the home computer changed the way people typed and communicated and
没错。因为家用电脑改变了人们打字、交流以及
did all these different things. And so it's revolutionary because it introduced a big
做各种不同事情的方式。所以它是革命性的，因为它带来了巨大的
change.
改变。
That's right. Okay. So revolutionary. Towards the end of Mr. Ford's dialogue, he said that
没错。好的。所以是革命性的。在福特先生对话的结尾，他说
they're going to have a Q&A section and he left us with a quote that according to him
他们将有一个问答环节，并且他留给我们一句引语，据他所说
sums up everything we've discussed today.
这句话总结了我们今天讨论的所有内容。
Okay. To sum up. This is very related to the word to summarize. It means to say in fewer
好的。总结一下。这与“概括”这个词非常相关。意思是用更少的
words. Okay. So this quote says what he wants to say, but it says it in a very short space.
词语来表达。好的。所以这句引语说出了他想说的，但用非常简短的方式。
So if we read a book and I ask you to sum up the story, this is basically I'm asking
所以如果我们读了一本书，我让你总结一下故事，这基本上就是我在要求
for a summary.
一个概要。
That's right. So I could say, you know, the Harry Potter story is a story about a young
没错。所以我可以这样说，你知道，哈利·波特的故事是关于一个年轻的
boy who is a wizard who loses his parents, who goes to school with his friends and learns
男孩，他是一个巫师，失去了父母，和朋友们一起去学校学习
about his powers.
他的能力。
That's a perfect way to sum up the Harry Potter story. All right. Very good.
这是总结哈利·波特故事的完美方式。好的，非常好。
So that's about it for language takeaway today, but we have some great phrases coming up for
这就是今天语言要点的全部内容，但我们接下来还有一些很棒的短语。
you in Fluency Builder. Let's listen to the dialogue again first and we'll be back in
你在流利度训练中。我们先再听一遍对话，稍后回来。
a moment.
一会儿。
Right everyone, I apologize that I can't show you the marketing campaign today, but next
各位，很抱歉我今天无法展示营销活动，但下周你们都将有机会亲眼看到。
week you will all have the opportunity to see it for yourselves. And I have no doubt
我毫不怀疑你们会印象深刻。让我总结一下我的关键点来结束这次演示。
that you will be impressed. Let me wrap up the presentation by summarizing my key points.
正如我一开始提到的，2010年对Alpha Computers来说是关键的一年。
As I mentioned at the outset, 2010 represents a key year for Alpha Computers. The recession
经济衰退 hopefully 已经过去。在计算机行业，每个人都清楚需求正在蓬勃发展，
is hopefully behind us. It is clear to everyone in the computer industry that demand is booming,
尤其是在发展中市场。如果我们要在这个竞争激烈的领域取得成功，
especially in the developing markets. If we're to succeed in this ultra competitive field,
那么我们必须全力推进，为客户提供满足他们各方面需求的产品。
then we really need to push forward and offer our customers products that meet their needs
正如我希望我已经说明的那样，X420代表了能够真正满足这些需求的电脑类型。
on all levels.
我向你们介绍了我们预计在2010年通过新的X420系列实现的收入情况，
As I hope I've illustrated, the X420 represents the kind of computer that can really satisfy
相信我，这真的只是开始。一旦我们在市场上站稳X420，
those needs. I gave you an idea of the kind of revenue we expect to hit in 2010 with the
我们计划继续用更具革命性和令人印象深刻的产品来扩展我们的产品线。
new X420 range, and believe me, this is really just the beginning. Once we establish the
Alpha Computers致力于创新和改进。
X420 in the market, we have plans to continue to expand our range with ever more revolutionary
只要我们坚持我之前强调的原则——质量、卓越和服务，
and impressive products. Alpha Computers is dedicated to innovation and improvement. I
我真的认为我们的潜力是无限的。
really see no limit in our potential as long as we stick to the principles I stressed earlier,
在进入问答环节之前，我想用一句名言来结束，
quality, excellence, and service.
这句话真正总结了我们今天讨论的一切，希望它能给你们带来和我一样的启发。
Before we move on to the Q&A section, I'd really like to leave you with a quote that
正如伟大的亨利·福特曾经说过的，质量意味着
really sums up everything that we've discussed today, and hopefully it will provide you with
做正确的事，即使没有人看着。
the same inspiration that it gives me. As the great Henry Ford once said, quality means
谢谢。
doing it right when no one is looking. Well, in fact, our customers are looking. They're
在没人看着的时候也要把事情做好。其实，我们的客户都在看着。他们
looking for us to lead the way and to give them the quality that our competitors cannot.
期待我们引领方向，提供竞争对手无法企及的质量。
We cannot let them down.
我们不能让他们失望。
All right, we're back. So now let's take a look at four key phrases on Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了。现在来看看流畅表达中的四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流畅表达。
So the first phrase we've got here in Fluency Builder is an interesting one, and I think
流畅表达中的第一个短语很有意思，我觉得
it's important to point out because we've got a verb and a noun that often go together.
有必要指出来，因为这里有一个动词和一个名词经常搭配使用。
Mr. Ford said this kind of computer can really satisfy those needs that customers have.
福特先生说，这种电脑能真正满足客户的需求。
That's right. So the phrase there is to satisfy a need. And as you said, this verb and this
没错。所以这个短语就是“满足需求”。正如你所说，这个动词和这个
noun usually go together. You want to satisfy your customers' needs.
名词通常一起使用。你要满足客户的需求。
All right, so what do I need? I need a good computer that is fast that I can do my business
好的，那我需要什么？我需要一台速度快、能处理业务的电脑。
on. And this computer, the X420, satisfies that need. It does what I need it to do.
而这款X420电脑就满足了那个需求。它做到了我需要它做的事。
Okay, so we understand the verb to satisfy, but the phrase is a very powerful phrase,
好，我们理解动词“满足”，但这个短语非常有力，
especially if you use it in business where you're saying we are giving our customers
尤其是在商业场合使用，表示我们正在给客户
what they need and we are making them happy.
他们需要的东西，并让他们满意。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay. As he continued talking about the X420, he said this is just the beginning.
好。当他继续谈论X420时，他说这只是个开始。
All right, so this is something we often say when we have a long project or plan. You can
好的，当我们有一个长期项目或计划时，经常这么说。你可以
say, yes, things are good now, but this is just the beginning. All right, there are many
说，是的，现在情况不错，但这只是开始。好，还有很多
good things to come. And this is something we often say in a positive way. Yes, this
好事在后面。这通常是一种积极的表达方式。是的，这
is good, but expect better things in the future.
不错，但未来期待更好的事情。
Very good. Okay, so this is just the beginning. And well, as he continued talking about the
很好。好的，所以这只是个开始。嗯，当他继续谈论这家公司时，
company, he said that the customers are looking for us to lead the way.
他说客户期望我们引领方向。
Okay, so this is an interesting phrase because he's making a comparison with other companies
好的，这是一个有趣的短语，因为他正在与其他公司做比较，
and he's saying, listen, our customers have many needs, but they want us to really be
他说，听着，我们的客户有很多需求，但他们希望我们真正
ahead of them and to innovate and to make new things and new computers that will be
走在他们前面，进行创新，制造新东西和新电脑，从而
ahead of the competition. So take the lead, be in the front.
领先于竞争对手。所以，要带头，要走在前面。
So basically the phrase to lead the way is for you to be in the front and give people
所以基本上，“引领方向”这个短语就是让你走在前面，为人们
a clear path.
开辟一条清晰的道路。
Think of Usain Bolt, that runner in the Olympics. Everyone's running quickly, but all of a sudden
想想尤塞恩·博尔特，那位奥运会短跑运动员。每个人都在快速奔跑，但突然之间
he takes the lead. He leads the way. He is ahead of everyone else. All the other runners
他领先了。他引领方向。他领先于其他所有人。所有其他选手
are far, far behind him.
都远远落在他后面。
That's right. Okay, so he's leading the way and he finishes his monologue by saying, we
没错。好的，所以他引领方向，并以这样的话结束了他的独白：我们
cannot let them down. We cannot let our customers down, basically. So the phrase here is to
不能让他们失望。基本上就是我们不能让客户失望。所以这里的短语是
let someone down.
“让某人失望”。
He let me down. We let them down. This is a great phrase and you can use it about anybody.
他让我失望了。我们让他们失望了。这是一个很棒的短语，你可以用它来形容任何人。
And it's a really important phrase because it means to disappoint someone. So for example,
这是一个非常重要的短语，因为它意味着让某人失望。例如，
Marco, when you forgot my birthday, you really let me down.
马可，当你忘记我的生日时，你真的让我失望了。
Okay, so that means I disappointed you because I forgot your birthday. So to let someone
好的，所以这意味着我让你失望了，因为我忘了你的生日。所以“让某人
down is to disappoint them, to not do what you were expected to do.
失望”就是让他们失望，没有做到他们期望你做的事。
Exactly. And so a company can do this. For example, when a company like Toyota makes
没错。所以公司可以这样做。例如，当像丰田这样的公司制造
a car that has many problems, that company lets down its customers.
一辆有很多问题的汽车时，那家公司就让它的客户失望了。
So you can let someone down. Basically, you have to have the subject. You let someone
所以你可以让某人失望。基本上，你必须有一个主语。你让某人
down or the company let down its customers.
失望，或者公司让它的客户失望。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay. A lot of great stuff here. Why don't we take one last listen and we'll be back
好的。这里有很多精彩内容。我们不如再听一遍，然后稍后
in a bit.
再回来。
Right everyone, I apologize that I can't show you the marketing campaign today, but next
各位，很抱歉我今天不能向你们展示营销活动，但下周
week you will all have the opportunity to see it for yourselves. And I have no doubt
你们所有人都有机会亲眼看到。我毫不怀疑
that you will be impressed. Let me wrap up the presentation by summarizing my key points.
你们会印象深刻。让我总结一下我的关键点来结束这次演示。
As I mentioned at the outset, 2010 represents a key year for Alpha Computers. The recession
正如我在开始时提到的，2010年对Alpha电脑来说是关键的一年。经济衰退
is hopefully behind us. It is clear to everyone in the computer industry that demand is booming,
希望已经过去。在电脑行业，每个人都很清楚需求正在激增，
especially in the developing markets. If we are to succeed in this ultra-competitive field,
尤其是在发展中市场。如果我们要在这个竞争极其激烈的领域取得成功，
then we really need to push forward and offer our customers products that meet their needs
那么我们就需要大力推进，为客户提供在各方面
on all levels. As I hope I've illustrated, the X420 represents the kind of computer that
满足他们需求的产品。正如我希望我已经说明的那样，X420代表了那种
can really satisfy those needs.
真正能满足这些需求的电脑。
I gave you an idea of the kind of revenue we expect to hit in 2010 with the new X420
我让你们了解了我们预计在2010年通过新的X420系列达到的收入水平，
range, and believe me, this is really just the beginning. Once we establish the X420
相信我，这真的只是开始。一旦我们在市场上确立了X420
in the market, we have plans to continue to expand our range with ever more revolutionary
的地位，我们计划继续用更具革命性
and impressive products.
和令人印象深刻的产品来扩展我们的产品线。
Alpha Computers is dedicated to innovation and improvement. I really see no limit in
Alpha Computers 致力于创新和改进。我真的看不到
our potential as long as we stick to the principles I stressed earlier, quality, excellence, and
只要我们坚持我之前强调的原则——质量、卓越和
service.
服务——我们的潜力有任何极限。
Before we move on to the Q&A section, I'd really like to leave you with a quote that
在我们进入问答环节之前，我真的很想留给你们一句名言，
really sums up everything we've discussed today, and hopefully it will provide you with
它真正总结了我们今天讨论的一切，希望它能给你们带来
the same inspiration that it gives me. As the great Henry Ford once said, quality means
和我一样的灵感。正如伟大的亨利·福特曾经说过的，质量意味着
doing it right, when no one is looking. Well, in fact, our customers are looking. They are
在没人看着的时候把事情做对。嗯，事实上，我们的客户正在看着。他们
looking for us to lead the way and to give them the quality that our competitors cannot.
期待我们引领方向，提供我们的竞争对手无法提供的质量。
We cannot let them down.
我们不能让他们失望。
Alright guys, so this is the penultimate lesson about presentation skills. As you saw, we
好了，各位，这是关于演讲技巧的倒数第二课。正如你们所见，我们
are summarizing and concluding the presentation, and there are actually a lot of great things
正在总结和结束演讲，这里其实有很多值得学习的好东西，
here to learn from, especially the vocab where you're saying, okay, let's sum things up,
尤其是那些词汇，比如“好了，让我们总结一下”，
to wrap it up, to conclude, to summarize.
“收尾”、“结束”、“概括”。
Summarize the key points, yeah. But there are also some important things coming up next
总结关键点，是的。但下周还有一些重要的内容要讲。
week. That's the very, very last part of this series, because usually after a presentation,
那是这个系列的最后一课，因为通常在演讲之后，
there is a section for questions and answers. That's called Q&A, and that's the topic of
会有一个问答环节。这叫做 Q&A，也是我们下一期节目的主题。
our next show. So you guys should stay tuned for that.
所以你们应该继续关注。
Alright, so we'll see you guys next time, and of course, if you have any questions or
好了，我们下次再见，当然，如果你们有任何问题或
comments, you will always find us at EnglishPod.com.
评论，随时可以在 EnglishPod.com 找到我们。
See you guys there.
那里见。
Bye.
再见。
Lauren, we have a lot of questions.
Lauren，我们有很多问题。